<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<source>
	
<!-- MAIN INFO ********************************************************** -->


<!-- Component name -->
<component>Local bus 8b IOS bridge - master 16b --> 8b</component>


<!-- Authors -->
<authors>
       <author login="solanka">Lukas Solanka</author>
</authors>


<!-- Features -->
<features>
    <item>Master part of the local bus IOS bridge</item>
    <item>8b local bus data width and 1b BE signal</item>
    <item>Needs 23 pins (LB16 needs 40 pins) - 17 pins saving</item>
    <item>No bursts - every 2nd cycle 16b transmission</item>
    <item>
        High latency - it may be necessary to raise LB_ROOT's ABORT cycle
    </item>
    <item>
        Connection directly to IOS pins. Don't forget to add regiob_*
        registers constraint to your UCF.
    </item>
</features>


<!-- Bugs -->
<bugs>
	<item>ABORT_N signal is probably not properly handled</item>
</bugs>


<!-- Things to do -->
<todo>
    <item>Hardware tests</item>
</todo>


<!-- Short Block description -->
<description>
    <p>
        This component should be used if there is not enough IOS pins for data
        transmission from an interface card to the COMBO6X card.
    </p>

    <p>
        It multiplexes 16b local bus data width to one 8b data path and also
        multiplexes two BE signals into 1. Thus, 17 IOS pins can be used for some
        other purpose (mostly data transmission). With this saving we are for
        instance able to transmit 64b width framelink from XFP2 card to COMBO6X.
    </p>
    <p>
        This is the master part of the IOS bridge and should be used on that
        card where the LB_ROOT component is present.
    </p>
</description>


<!-- COMPONENT INTERFACE ************************************************ -->
<interface>

	<!-- Port description -->
	<port_map>
        <divider>Common signals</divider>		
      <port  name="RESET" dir="in" width="1">
         Global component reset.
      </port>

      <port  name="CLK" dir="in" width="1">
         Global FPGA clock
      </port>

      <port  name="CLK8" dir="in" width="1">
         Clock on which LB8 interface is clocked. This will mostly be clock
         coming from an interface card.
      </port>


        <divider>Input interface</divider>		
      <port  name="LB16" dir="inout" width="16">
          16b local bus interface. This is an input master interface
      </port>


        <divider>Output interface</divider>		
      <port  name="LB8" dir="inout" width="8">
          8b local bus interface. Must be connected directly to IOS.
      </port>
    </port_map>
</interface>


<!-- HW BODY SECTION **************************************************** -->
<!-- information for HW designers, structure should be as follow          -->
<body>
    <p>
        Master IOS bridge component consists of two distinct parts: a part that
        <b>sends requests</b> to the slave associated component and a part that
        <b>waits for incoming data</b> and rdy signals from the slave component.
    </p>

    <p>
        Input FIFO stores incoming reqeuests (up to 16 requests, as defined in
        the local bus specification). Data bus and two BE signals are then
        multiplexed into 8b wide data bus and 1b wide BE signal. This data,
        together with control signals are then driven via IOB registers on the
        component's output (LB8).
    </p>

    <p>
        The latter part receives multiplexed incoming 8b data and BE signals,
        concatenates this data to form 16b and 2b wide data and BE bus, then
        drives the result on the LB16 interface. ERR_N signal is not multiplexed
        so it is just driven via IOB register directly on the LB16 interface.
    </p>

    <p>
        The component's figure is on the following picture (lb8_16_ios_bridge):
        <obr src="./fig/lb8_ios_bridge.fig">
            Local bus 8b IOS bridge structure (both associated components)
        </obr>
    </p>

    <h2>Note</h2>
    <p>
        Because of the 8b multiplex, the local bus interconnection on the card,
        where the slave component is present, will not support any burst
        transmissions.
    </p>

    <h2>Used components</h2>
    <p>
        <ul>
            <li>
                <ref_comp ref="fifo">FIFO component</ref_comp>
            </li>
        </ul>
    </p>
</body>

</source>
