<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<source>
	
<!-- MAIN INFO ********************************************************** -->


<!-- Component name -->
<component>Local bus 8b IOS bridge - slave 8b --> 16b</component>


<!-- Authors -->
<authors>
       <author login="solanka">Lukas Solanka</author>
</authors>


<!-- Features -->
<features>
    <item>Slave part of the local bus IOS bridge</item>
    <item>8b local bus data width and 1b BE signal</item>
    <item>Needs 23 pins (LB16 needs 40 pins) - 17 pins saving</item>
    <item>No bursts - every 2nd cycle 16b transmission</item>
    <item>
        High latency - it may be necessary to raise LB_ROOT's ABORT cycle
    </item>
    <item>
        Connection directly to IOS pins. Don't forget to add regiob_*
        registers constraint to your UCF.
    </item>
</features>


<!-- Bugs -->
<bugs>
	<item>ABORT_N signal is probably not properly handled</item>
</bugs>


<!-- Things to do -->
<todo>
    <item>Hardware tests</item>
</todo>


<!-- Short Block description -->
<description>
    <p>
        This component should be used if there is not enough IOS pins for data
        transmission from an interface card to the COMBO6X card.
    </p>

    <p>
        It multiplexes 16b local bus data width to one 8b data path and also
        multiplexes two BE signals into 1. Thus, 17 IOS pins can be used for some
        other purpose (mostly data transmission). With this saving we are for
        instance able to transmit 64b width framelink from XFP2 card to COMBO6X.
    </p>
    <p>
        This is a slave part of the IOS bridge and should NOT be used on the
        card where the LB_ROOT component is present (i.e. mainly an iterface
        card).
    </p>
</description>


<!-- COMPONENT INTERFACE ************************************************ -->
<interface>

	<!-- Port description -->
	<port_map>
        <divider>Common signals</divider>		
      <port  name="RESET" dir="in" width="1">
         Global component reset.
      </port>

      <port  name="CLK" dir="in" width="1">
         Global FPGA clock
      </port>


        <divider>Input interface</divider>		
      <port  name="LB8" dir="inout" width="8">
          8b local bus interface. Should be connected directly to IOS.
      </port>


        <divider>Output interface</divider>		
      <port  name="LB16" dir="inout" width="16">
          16b local bus interface. Output.
      </port>
    </port_map>
</interface>


<!-- HW BODY SECTION **************************************************** -->
<!-- information for HW designers, structure should be as follow          -->
<body>
    <p>
        Slave IOS bridge component consists of two distinct parts, which are
        dual to its associated (master) component: a <b>part that splits
        mulitplexed</b> 8b wide <b>data</b> bus and 1b wide BE signal into the
        double of their sizes and the <b>part</b> that waits for read data and
        <b>multiplexes them into half the wide bus</b> (data and BE).
    </p>

    <p>
        The component's figure is on the following picture (lb8_16_ios_bridge):
        <obr src="./fig/lb8_ios_bridge.fig">
            Local bus 8b IOS bridge structure (both associated components)
        </obr>
    </p>

    <p>
        Input data (8b --> 16b) pass through IOB registers. DWR and BE signals
        are merged into 16b (2b) signals asing additional registers pipeline
        stage. Control signals (ADS_N, WR_N, RD_N) are then controlled by the
        cnt_merge counter which enables them every second valid cycle. Valid
        cycle is determined by these control signals passing through IOB
        registers (see picture). The responsibility to generate appropriate 2
        clocks of control signals on the 8b bus for each clock on the 16b bus is
        on the masters component. So <b>if there is a problem with consistency
        data and control signals, try to debug also the master component</b>
    </p>

    <p>
        The otput part (16b --> 8b) consists of a FIFO in case some components
        generate any bursts (although that should not happen if there is a
        connection of master -- slave components). FIFO readout and the output
        multiplex is controlled by the cnt_rdy counter (see picture).
    </p>

    <h2>Note</h2>
    <p>
        Because of the 8b multiplex, the local bus interconnection on the card,
        where the slave component is present, will not support any burst
        transmissions.
    </p>

    <h2>Used components</h2>
    <p>
        <ul>
            <li>
                <ref_comp ref="fifo">FIFO component</ref_comp>
            </li>
        </ul>
    </p>
</body>

</source>
